Guide to the Howard Dunham Barlow Collection, 1911-2000 (Bulk 1920-1958), MS001 MS 001
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series 7: Photographs, 1938-ca 1960
  - HDB with unidentified man [director?], ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - HDB with unidentified woman, ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - HDB and Voice of Firestone Orchestra and Chorus, Dec 14, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - HDB and Voice of Firestone Orchestra, ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    (posed)
  - HDB and Raymond C. Firestone with two (unidentified) young people, ca.1953 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - HDB, Raymond C. Firestone and David Sarnoff, President of NBC, ca.1955 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - HDB and Voice of Firestone Chorus/ Orchestra in rehearsal for telecast, ca.1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - HDB in conducting Voice of Firestone Orchestra during telecast and with Nadine Connor, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - HDB and representatives of Kuwait during tour of the NBC Radio and television Studios, Aug 24, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - HDB conducting American Legion Drum Corps Post No.29 Greenwich, CT at opening of Greenwich Federal Savings and Loan Assn, Jul 3, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    (five photos)
  - HDB conducting Miami Pops, ca.1960 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - HDB formal portrait, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    (five photos and one slide)
  - HDB proof portraits, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    (19 4x5)
  - HDB studio portrait, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - HDB conducting Firestone Symphony Orchestra, ca. 1950 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - HDB with Voice of Firestone Orchestra, ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Eleanor Steber, ca.1950 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Obituary: Raymond C. Firestone, New York Times, Sep 12, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Series 8: Prospective Scripts by HDB, ca 1960
  - They All Made Music, ca.1960 (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Music Notes, ca.1960 (Box 7, Folder 6-9)
  - Ideas for Radio and TV Programs About Music, ca.1960 (Box 7, Folder 10-14)
  - Keyboard Jr. and Young Keyboard Jr., 1961-1965 (Box 7, Folder 15-18)
- Series 9: Scrapbooks
  Original Scrapbooks in rear of box
  - Scrapbook 1: History of the Musical Career of Howard D. Barlow, 1911-1924
    - Title Page: High School Graduation Program, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Pages 1-4: Reed College Portland, 1912-1914 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Pages 5-6: New York City, 1915-1917 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Pages 7-20: Bay View Festival, Bay View, MI, Aug 1917 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Pages 21-26: New York City and Camp Greene, NC, 1916-1917 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Pages 27-30: Charlotte Music Festival, May 1918; and MacDowell Colony National Federation of Music Clubs, July 1919, 1918-1919 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Musical America, p.1, 3-6, Jul 12, 1919 (Box OS 10)
    - Pages 31-36: New York City Activities, 1919-1920 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Pages 37-44: Portland, OR, Forest Children, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Pages 45-58: New York City Activities, Choral, 1921-1923 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Pages 59-72 (end): American National Orchestra, 1923-1924 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook II, The "CBS Years," 1927-1939
    - Pages 1-14, 1927-1929 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Pages 15-30, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Pages 31-40, 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Pages 41-52, 1933-1935 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Pages 53-69 (end), 1936-1939 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Series 10: Writings: Newspapers and Magazines, 1924-1969
  - Articles, 1939-1958 (Box 5, Folder 24-26)
    Will America Support Music Made in America? Musical Monitor December 1923: 25
    Radio's Insatiable Appetite. Radio Guide (undated): 4
    What About Tomorrow. Up Beat April 1939: 23
    The Democracy of Radio. The Etude vol. LVII.6 (1939): 367, 421
    Straight from the Shoulder. Musical Digest (undated): 17, 42
    Don Tranter, Announcing….. (Howard Barlow guest editor)Courier-Express: August 1942
    A Conductor Looks at Contemporary Composition. Music Publishers Journal September-October 1943: 7, 48
    Jameson, William. "'I Lost My Shirt-Playing American Music!' says Howard Barlow ." (unknown magazine) undated
    Practical Music. Music Educators Journal January 1952: 23-25.
    Practical Music. Music Educators Journal February/March 1952: 32-36.
    Music-The Vitamin of the Soul. The Delta September 1958: 10-11. December 1923: 25
  - Let's Modernize Opera, says Howard Barlow. The Microphone. The Original U. S. Radio Newspaper January 1936: 16. (Box OS 10)
  - Lectures on Orchestral Conducting, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 1-9)
    (3 copies) Introduction, p. 1-42
    Beethoven, Ludwig. Symphony #1 in C Major, Op. 21, p.43-76
    Copland, Aaron. An Outdoor Overture, p.77-89
    Wagner, Richard. Prelude. Die Meistersinger von Nuremburg, p.90-110
    Original Drafts of Lectures on Orchestral Conducting 1969-1970
    The Conductor (draft of notes)
    Symphony # 1, Beethoven
    An Outdoor Overture, Aaron Copland
    Chapter IV, Prelude to Die Meistersinger von Nuernberg, Richard Wagner 1969
    Chapter V, Romeo & Juliette, Tchaikowsky 1970
    Chapter VI, Finlandia, Sibelius 1970
    Chapter VII, Symphony No. 5, Beethoven
    The Firebird, Igor Stravinsky
  - Our Family by Howard Arthur Steck, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Geneology of the Barlow family.
- Series 11: Phonograph Records
  - Columbia Masterworks Set No. M370. Hayden: Symphony No. 98 in B Flat Major (Salomon No.4), 1937 (Box MR_LP)
    Played by Howard Barlow conducting the Columbia Broadcasting Symphony (three 78 rpm disks)
  - Columbia Masterworks Set X-165: Liszt, Orpheus., 1937 (Box MR_LP)
    Howard Barlow conducting the Columbia Broadcasting Symphony(two 78 rpm disks)
  - Columbia Masterworks Set No. 363: Hayden Symphony No. 94, in G. Major ("Surprise")(Salomon No. 3), 1937 (Box MR_LP)
  - Columbia Masterworks Set No. 350: Deems Taylor, Through the Looking Glass, Suite for Orchestra, Op. 12, 1937 (Box MR_LP)
    Played by Howard Barlow Conducting the Columbia Symphony Orchestra(four 78 rpm disks)
- Series 12: Miscellany
  - Camp Greene, 1917-1918 (Box OS 10)
  - Christmas Music, undated (Box OS 10)
  - Here's to the Boys, undated (Box OS 10)
    (music by HDB, words by David Ovens)
  - Bussler, Ludwig. Practical Harmony, a systematic course in fifty-four lessons. Philadelphia: Hatch Music Company, 1896 (Box OS 10)
  - scraps, undated (Box OS 10)
    Also contains manuscripts for 1812 overature, Rigaletto by Verdi, Symphony in G minor by Mozart, Marriage of Figgaro by Mozart, Meistersinger Choral finale, and Kazan-Boris
  - Miscellany of Favorite Pieces for the Violin, undated (Box OS 10)
  - Fear not ye O Isreal, 1889 (Box OS 10)
  - Hold Thou My Hand, 1904 (Box OS 10)
  - If he can fight like he can love good-night germany!, 1918 (Box OS 10)
- Series 13: Research Materials on the Life of Howard Dunham Barlow
  - Inventory
    - Inventory List and Correspondence, 1989-1999 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Biographical Articles
    - Written by James Pegolotti, 1992-1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Written by various authors, 1938-1989 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Written by HDB, ca.1930 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Barlow Family Genealogy
    - From John Barlow (ca 1605) to HDB, 1889-1994 (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
    - Aspects of The History of the State of Ohio, 1941-1942 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Barlow of Barlow Notebook, compiled by A. Maxim Coppage, FSA Scot, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - HDB Early Years in Ohio and Illinois
    - Plain City, Ohio, Birthplace, 1874-1953 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
    - Plain City, Ohio, Trip by JP, incl. photographs, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Plain City Advocate, Apr 1992 (Box OS 10)
    - Urbana, Ohio, HDB Recollections and Newspaper Articles, incl. photographs of HDB home, 1893-1900 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
    - Barlow & Kent Furniture Plant, incl. photographs, 1893-1900 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Mt. Carmel, Illinois, HDB Recollections and Newspaper Articles, 1903-1909 (Box 10, Folder 17-18)
    - Racism in Urbana and Mt. Carmel, 1897-1907 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - College and New York City Experiences
    - Reed College, 1912-1915 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Choral Director, Camp Green, NC, 1917 (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
    - American National Orchestra, 1923-1924 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - League of Composers, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Neighborhood Playhouse, 1925-1927 (Box 10, Folder 25-28)
  - Conductor
    - CBS. History of network and 3 audio cassettes: CBS at 50, 1932-1935 (Box 10, Folder 29-30)
    - CBS. First day of broadcast, Sep 18, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - CBS. William Paley, ca.1930 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - CBS. Davidson Taylor, Head, Music Division, ca.1930 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - CBS. March of Time, ca.1930 (Box 10, Folder 34-36)
    - CBS. Everybody's Music, Composer commissions, 1937-1938 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - CBS. HDB's 1938 invitation to new composers to submit works (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - CBS. Everybody's Music, Wendel Diebel, pianist and composer plays, Aug 21, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 39-42)
    - CBS. Recordings by HDB with Columbia Orchestra, ca.1940-1950 (Box 10, Folder 43-44)
    - Columbia Masterworks Poster, Jun 1942 (Box OS 10)
    - CBS. Serious Music, List of performances and commissions, 1927-1941 (Box 10, Folder 45-46)
      1. Notes on the Broadcasting of Serious Music at Columbia, by Oliver Daniels 1937-1941. 16 p.
      2. Serious Music on the Columbia Broadcasting System. A Survey Of Series, Soloists and Special Performances from 1927 through 1938. 67 p.
  - HDB: Misc. Conducting engagements, 1940-1946
    - Baltimore Symphony, 1940-1942 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - HDB: Guest conductor of New York Philharmonic, 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Columbia Masterworks Proudly Salutes the New York Philharmonic Orchestra A Living Tradition of Greatness, ca.1950 (Box OS 10)
    - HDB: Conductor on Harvest of Stars radio program, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - HDB: Conductor on Voice of Firestone radio program, 1943-1958
    - History of program, 1928-1963 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Weekly log of soloists, 1941-1963 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Varia on Barlow's conducting, 1943-1958 (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - TV Simulcasts, 1948-1980 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Varia on commercial release of telecasts, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Audio cassettes, 1938-1943 (Box 10, Folder 55)
      a. 10th anniversary program 12/5/38 w/Richard Crooks
      b. 25th anniversary broadcast 11/30/53
      c. Eleanor Steiber 5/24/48 and Thomas L. Thomas 12/12/48
      d. Rehearsal (Howard Barlow Sings, subbing for late soloist)
    - Julian Work, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Christopher Lynch, 1946-1994 (Box 10, Folder 57)
      (incl. 2 photographs and audio cassette)
    - Eleanor Steber, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - The Bethel Years, 1965-1972
    - The Bethel Years, incl. text for orchestral conducting, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Final illness and death, January 31, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Jeanette Barlow, 1929-1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      (wife)
    - Roger Plummer, 1989-1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      (nephew)
  - Materials on professional colleagues
    - Sophie Braslau, 1913-1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Sophie Braslau, Opera Shanewis, 1918-1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - John Erskine, 1951-1994 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Eileen Farrell, 1943-1992 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Lucille Fletcher, 1938-1991 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Morton Gould, 1992-1996 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Bernard Herrmann, 1985-1992 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Ernest Hutcheson, 1941-1993 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Arthur Judson, 1950-1982 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      (manager), Oral History Memoir
    - Arthur Judson, 1940-1996 (Box 11, Folder 15)
      (manager)
    - Arthur Judson, 1916-1947 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      (manager), New York Times articles
    - Arthur Judson, 1952-1992 (Box 11, Folder 17-19)
      (manager), on importance
    - Arthur Judson, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 20)
      (grandson) (manager), Interview by JP of AJ II
    - Arthur Judson (manager), Genealogy, 1886-1978 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Mitch Miller, Oboist, 1956-1995 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Oscar Shumsky, Violinist, 1990-2000 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Rise Stevens, Soprano, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Donald Voorhees, Conductor, 1968-1991 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Materials on the history of broadcasting
    - Broadcasting History, Overview Articles of Early Radio, 1946-1982 (Box 11, Folder 26-29)
    - Broadcasting History, Radio Varia, 1928-1993 (Box 11, Folder 30-32)
    - Broadcasting History, Personal Recollections, 1935-1954 (Box 11, Folder 33-35)
    - Broadcasting History, Network Radio Log by Jay Hickerson, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Broadcasting History, Serious Music on Radio, 1928-1987 (Box 11, Folder 37-38)
    - Broadcasting History, Radio Advertising, 1938-1993 (Box 11, Folder 39-40)
    - Broadcasting History, Radio Receivers: shapes, 1927-1975 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Research Sources
    - Library of Congress lists of CBS radio tapes, 1982-1993 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - University of Maryland's Library of American Broadcasting, 1988-1996 (Box 11, Folder 43-45)
    - Museum of Television and Radio, ca.1930-1940 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Primary Source Archives, undated (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Columbia University Oral History List, undated (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Original inventories of the collection, 2002 (Box 11)